Contact

305 331 2309 (Mobile) nmelo00@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nelsonmelog (LinkedIn)

hpdrc.fiu.edu/rac/preview2/alta1/nmelo/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Weather

Meteorology

Research

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual)

Publications

On Water Renewal and Salinity Variability in the Northeast Subregion of Florida Bay

Community metabolism in shallow coral reef and seagrass ecosystems, Lower Florida Keys

Book: "SOUTH FLORIDA MARINE ENVIRONMENTS: An ecological synthesis"

Reporte de un frente hidrológico al NE de la Península de Yucatán. Manifestaciones físicas, químicas e hidrobiológicas".

On Florida Bay hypersalinity and water exchange

Nelson Melo

Senior Researcher at ALTAMETRY Inc.

Miami, Florida

Summary

My main interests include Physical Oceanography and Remote Sensing.

I had been Oceanographer since 1978 and a Research Oceanographer at Atlantic Oceanographic and Meteorological Laboratory (AOML) NOAA since 2001. Now working at Florida International University.

If you'd like to know more about my work, you might peruse my ongoing projects or my Curriculum Vitae and Publications:

http://cake.fiu.edu/Melo/

Actually I am working in the following topics:

- High resolution Remote Sensing applications to Coastal Oceanography.
- Regional hydrography and circulation of south Florida coastal waters.
- Circulation patterns and water mass transport into and out of the Caribbean Sea.
- Implementation of moored oceanographic sensor arrays.
- Development of real-time oceanographic monitoring stations.

Specialties: EXPERIENCE

Academic

Science Research: Oceanography and Marine Remote Sensing (remote sensors and aero-space digital images processing, applied to marine research).

Non-academic

AM Computers Corp. Science and Computer Instrumentation: Installation and operation of science, radio-location and computer instrumentation (computer and network installation, cabling, hardware and software, setup, operation and maintenance).

Experience

Florida International University / ALTAMETRY
Director of Marine Research, Senior Researcher
January 2014 - Present

Miami, Florida

Nelson Melo is in charge at ALTA Systems and Florida International University to develop of high-resolution Remote Sensing applications to Coastal Oceanography.

http://terrafly.com/

Miami University and Atlantic Oceanographic and Meteorological Laboratory In Miami, Florida, Unated States of America:

http://hpdrc.fiu.edu/rac/preview2/alta1/nmelo/

ALTA is a smart balloon which flies without fuel, or pilot to unreachable places, where it transmits images, and/ or other data to any internet screen. In one hour ALTA can deliver thousands of images from multiple perspectives, of the highest resolution, from the lowest angles, at the lowest cost. ALTA is the smallest, greenest earth imaging system in the world. This technology has been applied to marine research and marine environmental monitoring.

ALTAMETRY Inc.
Senior Researcher
January 2014 - Present
Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Alta Systems are supported all over the globe by the Alta Drifter Social Network which provides fellowship and information throughout the network. Every image and or data suitable for public consumption will appear on the internet as part of the world wide matrix of geo-referenced imagery.

http://www.altametry.com/

Cooperative Institute for Marine and Atmospheric Studies (CIMAS)
Research A. Senior

January 2001 - December 2013 (13 years)

http://cake.fiu.edu/Melo/

The Cooperative Institute for Marine and Atmospheric Studies (CIMAS) is a research institute of the University of Miami located in the Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science (RSMAS). CIMAS serves as a mechanism to bring together the research resources of the University with those of NOAA in order to develop a center of excellence in research that is relevant to understanding the Earth's oceans and atmosphere within the context of the NOAA's mission.

The scientific activities in CIMAS are organized under broad Research Themes. The Theme topics and their scientific objectives are guided by NOAA's Strategic Plan and its specific goals in the context of the research activities and expertise resident in the University and the local Miami laboratories of NOAA.

Atlantic Oceanographic and Meteorological Laboratory (AOML) Senior Oceanographic Researcher January 2001 - December 2013 (13 years)

http://cake.fiu.edu/Melo/

The Atlantic Oceanographic and Meteorological Laboratory (AOML) is one of the Oceanic and Atmospheric Research (OAR) Facilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). NOAA/AOML is a part of the US Department of Commerce (DOC) and is located in Miami, Florida. AOML's mission is to conduct basic and applied research in oceanography, tropical meteorology, atmospheric and oceanic chemistry, and acoustics. The research seeks to understand the physical characteristics and processes of the ocean and the atmosphere, both separately and as a coupled system.

Instituto de Oceanografia (Habana, Cuba) Researcher and Vice Director 1995 - 1999 (5 years)

Director of the Division of Research and Environment; Head of the Research Group in Marine Remote Sensing; Principal Investigator of the International Project with the European Space Agency (ESA): "Integrated study of coastal environment in Cuba using satellite SAR - ERS imagery (AO3–126)". Research Investigator.

Education

University of South Florida

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Remote Sensing - Physical

Oceanography · (1998 - 1999)

Habana University

Master, Nuclear Physics - Oceanography · (1973 - 1978)